Guide to the Papers of Mordecai Sheftall (1735-1797), undated, 1761-1867, 1873, 1932, 1941 (bulk 1777-1778) *P-12
American Jewish Historical Society, Newton Centre, MA and New York, NY
- Subgroup II: American Revolutionary and Continental Troop Commissarial Work and Provision Return Records, undated, 1777-1779, 1782-1783
  - Series II: Commissarial Records - Army, undated, 1777-1778
    - Subseries V: Provision Returns, Signed-Only, Illegible and Fragmented, undated, 1777-1778
      - (Binder 8)
        - Provision Return Signed by [Illegible] Received of Mordecai Sheftall Three Barrels of Flour, 11/00/1778 (Item 332)
        - Provision Return Signed by Cunningham for Capt. Cunningham and One Woman [Fragment], 11/01/1778 (Item 333)
        - Provision Return Signed by Robert Howe and Francis Moore for John Morrison, 11/06/1778 (Item 334)
        - Provision Return Signed by Robert Howe for Officers [Fragment], 11/06/1778 (Item 335)
        - Provision Return Signed by Samuel Camp and [Daniel Roberts] to Daniel Roberts from 03/20/[1778] to [Illegible], 11/11/1778 (Item 336)
        - Provision Return Signed by Robert Howe for [Illegible], 11/13/1778 (Item 337)
        - Provision Return Signed by William Wash for William Wall? [Slightly Illegible], 11/17/1778 (Item 338)
        - Provision Return Signed by William Wash for William Wall? [Slightly Illegible], 11/17/1778 (Item 339)
        - Provision Return Signed by John White for Robert Ellice for a Shank and Rice, 11/17/1778 (Item 340)
        - Provision Return Signed by John Morrison for One Subaltern, Two Sergeants, and Sixteen Privates Going on Command, 11/18/1778 (Item 341)
        - Provision Return Signed by [Robert Mosby] for One Man, 11/20/1778-11/30/1778 (Item 342)
        - Provision Return Signed by [Illegible] for Capt. Cunningham and One Bowman, 11/21/1778 (Item 343)
        - Provision Return Signed by James Hill for One Man and One Washerwoman for the Fourth Company [Fragment], 11/24/1778 (Item 344)
        - Provision Return Signed by Frederick Shick for Three Men and Three Women, 11/24/1778 (Item 345)
        - Provision Return Signed by Robert Ellis for Mrs. [Colonel] White for a Shank and a Roasting Piece, 11/24/1778; WPA_B-0121; Indexed #115 (Item 346)
        - Provision Return Signed by [Littleby Mosby] [Fragment, Somewhat Illegible], 11/27/[1778] (Item 347)
        - Provision Return Signed by John Farley for the Adjutant, 11/27/1778 (Item 348)
        - Provision Return Signed by James Galache for Rum for Twelve Privates, Sergeants, and First Lieutenant, 11/27/1778 (Item 349)
        - Provision Return Signed by Thomas Dowell for Seventeen Men on Guard at Coffee Bluff, 11/29/1778 (Item 350)
        - Provision Return Signed by [John Frazer] for John Baker, 11/30/1778 (Item 351)
        - Provision Return Signed by John Farley for the Adjutant, 12/01/1778 (Item 352)
        - Provision Return Signed by George Rain for One Man in the [D.Q.M.] Department on Fatigue for Three Days (Received by the Negro April), 12/02/1778-12/04/1778 (Item 353)
        - Provision Return Signed by [William] McIntosh for a Quarter of Good Beef and Rice, 12/03/1778; WPA_E-0201; Indexed #12; #129 (Item 354)
        - Provision Return Signed by the Mark of Peggy Sikes for Two Women Named Peggy Sikes and Their Seven Children, 12/08/1778; WPA_D-0295; Indexed #087 (Item 355)
        - Provision Return Signed by John McClure for One Gallon Rum for the Use of the Look-Out Boats, 12/[09]/1778; WPA_F-0411; Indexed #091 (Item 356)
        - Provision Return [Fragment], 12/10/1778 (Item 357)
        - Provision Return Signed by William Harris to Daniel Cuthbert, 12/17/1778 (Item 358)
        - Provision Return Signed by B. Cowper for Two Gallons of Rum for Col. Bull's Regiment, 12/17/1778 (Item 359)
        - Provision Return for Col. Bull's Regiment Signed by [Illegible], 12/17/1778 (Item 360)
        - Provision Return Signed by Henry Mulholland for Rum for Two-hundred and Forty Men, 12/19/1778 (Item 361)
        - Provision Return Signed by R. Mackenzie, 12/19/1778; WPA_F-0239; Indexed #047 (Item 362)
        - Provision Return Signed by [Torn] for Two-hundred and Sixty Rations for Col. Bull's Regiment, 12/19/1778 (Item 363)
    - Subseries VI: Provision Returns for the South Carolina Regiments, Battalions, and Units, undated, 1778
      This Subseries contains thirty-five Provision Returns specifically naming South Carolina Regiments, Battalions, and Units. A partial list of names from the Provision Returns are: John Vanderhorst, John Harrison, Peter Horn, Shem Cook, William Henderson, James Parham, Hugh Milling, John Detraville, Thomas Pickney, and Charles Warley. Many of the Provision Returns have illegible names recorded on the returns. South Carolina regiments and units specifically named are: the 6thRegiment, the 3rdRegiment and 3rdBattalion, the 2ndBrigade, the 2ndBattalion, the 2ndRegiment, the Artillery Detachment, and the 1stRegiment and 1stBattalion. Fort Howe and St. Catherine's Island are the only two named places within these South Carolina-specified Provision Returns.
      - (Binder 9)
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 6th Regiment Sick Signed by [Illegible], undated (Item 1 [001])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina Brigade Signed by John Vanderhorst with Partial [Torn] List of Numbers Provided for, undated (Item 2 [027])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina Signed by [Illegible], undated (Item 3 [028])
        - Provision Return for South Carolina Signed by Peter Horn for Ten Men, 05/09/1778 (Item 4 [002])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 3rd Regiment Unsigned for Those Under Command of Major Wise, 05/13/1778 (Item 5 [005])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 2nd Brigade Signed by John Harrison for One Corporal and [Torn] "doing duties at Fort Howe," [Fragment], 06/04/1778 (Item 6 [003])
        - Provision Return for South Carolina Battalions Signed by Shem Cook of the Second Battalion for Eighteen Men and [Eight] Women at Camp Howe, 06/05/1778 (Item 7 [026])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 6th Regiment Signed by William Henderson for Eighty-five Men, 06/06/1778 (Item 8 [032])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 1st Regiment Signed by James Parham with Numbers of Officers and Non-Coms for Col. Pinckney, 06/13/1778 (Item 9 [004])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 3rd Battalion Signed by Illegible, 06/19/1778 (Item 10 [010])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 1st Regiment Signed by [Illegible] with Numbers of Persons Provided for, 06/21/1778 (Item 11 [024])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 2nd Regiment Signed by [Illegible] for Rum for Those Under the Command of Major Wise, 06/21/1778 (Item 12 [025])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 2nd Regiment Signed by Hugh Milling for Rum, 06/21/1778 (Item 13 [030])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina Artillery Detachment Signed by John Detraville with Numbers of Persons Provided for, 06/21/1778 (Item 14 [031])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 6th Regiment Signed by William Henderson for Drums and Fifes, and Privates, 06/29/1778 (Item 15 [005])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 3rd Regiment Signed by J. Wise for Rum, 06/29/1778 (Item 16 [023])
        - Provision Return for South Carolina Brigade Signed by John Vanderhorst, 07/[?]1778 (Item 17 [012])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 1st Regiment Signed by Thomas Pinckney for Rum with Numbers of Persons Provided for, 07/02/1778 (Item 18 [022])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 3rd Regiment Signed by [Illegible] for Those Under Major Wise's Command, 07/04/1778 (Item 19 [020])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 1st Battalion Signed by Thomas Pinckney with Numbers of Persons Provided for, 07/04/1778 (Item 20 [021])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 3rd Regiment Signed by [Illegible] for Those Under Major Wise's Command, 07/09/1778 (Item 21 [018])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 3rd Regiment Signed by [Illegible] for Those Under Major Wise's Command, 07/10?/1778 (Item 22 [019])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 3rd Signed by [Wise?] with Numbers of Persons Provided for, 07/16/1778 (Item 23 [033])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina Detachment Signed by John Vanderhorst [Fragment], 07/16/1778 (Item 24 [034])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 1st Regiment Signed by John Vanderhorst, 07/19/1778 (Item 25 [035])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina Brigade Signed by John Vanderhorst for Five Sergeants, Three Drum and Fifes, and Fifty Rank and File, 07/19/1778 (Item 26 [036])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 1st Regiment Signed by John Vanderhorst, 07/20/1778 (Item 27 [006])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 3rd Regiment Signed by [?] Smith for Rum for Men Under the Command of Co. Pinckney, 07/20/1778 (Item 28 [017])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 1st Regiment Signed by John Vanderhorst, 07/21/1778 (Item 29 [007])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina Artillery Signed by John Detraville with Numbers of Officers and Non-Coms, 07/21/1778-07/23/1778 (Item 30 [008])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 6th Regiment Signed by John Detraville for the Drums, Fifes, Sergeants and Rank and File, 07/22/1778 (Item 31 [009])
        - Provision Return South Carolina 1st Regiment Signed by Capt. John Vanderhorst, 07/22/1778 (Item 32 [011])
        - Provision Return South Carolina 1st Regiment Signed by John Vanderhorst, 07/23/1778 (Item 33 [013])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina Artillery Detachment Under the Command of Capt. John De Treville for Rum, 07/24/1778 (Item 34 [015])
        - Provision Return for the South Carolina 3rd Regiment Signed by Ch. Warley for Molasses and Rum for the Use of the Troops on St. Catherine's Island, 07/24/1778; WPA_C-0031; Indexed #095 (Item 35 [016])
    - Subseries VII: Provision Returns for Multiple Battalions, 1778
      This Subseries contains eight Provision Returns with several Battalions named or both Georgia and South Carolina Brigades mentioned. Names include George St. George, Francis Moore and John Manley. Three Provision Returns (#4-#6) are "Lists of Provision Numbers for Georgia and South Carolina Brigades and Other Position Provided For."
      - (Binder 9)
        - Provision Return for 3rd and 4th Battalions Signed by George St. George for [Molasses] Due to Three Men of the 4th Battalion and Three Men of the 3rd Battalion at Mr. Read's Near Lake Ogechie [Ogeeches] "which the party is very indeferent & good opertunity to make Beer", 04/10/1778; WPA_E-0267; Indexed #102 (Item 1)
        - Provision Return for the 2nd and 3rd Battalion Signed by Francis Moore for Fifteen Men, Two Women, Five Children for Two Days, 04/18/1778 (Item 2)
        - Provision Return for the 4th Regiment and 4th Battalion Signed by [Illegible] with Names of and Numbers of Rations Provided for, 05/25/1778 (Item 3)
        - List of Provision Numbers for Georgia and South Carolina Brigades and Other Positions Provided for, 07/19/1778 (Item 4)
        - List of Provision Numbers for Georgia and South Carolina Brigades and Other Positions Provided for, 07/19/1778 (Item 5)
        - List of Provision Numbers for Georgia and South Carolina Brigades and Other Positions Provided for, 07/20/1778 (Item 6)
        - Provision Return for the 2nd and 4th Battalions Signed by [Illegible], 11/11/1778 (Item 7)
        - Provision Return for the 3rd and 4th Battalion Signed by John Manly for Part of Both Battalions, 12/02/1778? (Item 8)
    - Subseries VIII: Provision Returns for the Artificers, undated, 1778
      This subseries contains thirty-three Provision Returns for the Artificer Unit of the Continental Army of Georgia. This unit was in charge of constructing and maintaining arms for the military. The term is of British origin. These Provision Returns are primarily for the 3rdRegiment and 3rdBattalion. (See also Subseries III of the Series for more 3rdRegiment and 3rdBattalion Provision Returns.) Among those who signed the returns are: John Sutcliffe, Peter Taarling, John Peter Wagon, Gideon Booker, David Rainie, Thomas Booker, John Manley, Thomas Threadgill, John Wandin, John Phillips, John McIntosh, Thomas Lane, William Scott, Isaac Hicks and Robert Howe. One Provision Return specifically mentions canteen makers (#3). No specific places are mentioned in these returns.
      - (Binder 9)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd [Regiment?] Signed by John Peter Wagon and John Phillips, undated (Item 1)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by John Sutcliffe for Three Men, 03/06/1778 (Item 2)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by John Sutcliffe for the Canteen Makers, 03/11/1778 (Item 3)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by John Sutcliffe for Two Men, 03/16/1778 (Item 4)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by Peter Taarling for Two Men, 03/18/1778 (Item 5)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by Peter Taarling, 03/23/1778 (Item 6)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by John Peter Wagon, 08/07/1778 (Item 7)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by John Phillips for Those Now in Town, 08/24/1778 (Item 8)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by John McIntosh for Seven Men, 08/28/1778 (Item 9)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Wm. Scott Six Men, 08/28/1778 (Item 10)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by [Gideon] Booker for Six Men, 08/31/1778 (Item 11)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by Gideon Booker for Six Men, 09/01/1778 (Item 12)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Gideon Booker for Six Men, 09/02?/1778 (Item 13)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Thomas Lane for Six Men, 09/04/1778 (Item 14)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Thomas Phillips for Six Men, 09/07/1778 (Item 15)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by David Rainie for Six Men, 09/09/1778 (Item 16)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Rains Cook for Six Men, 09/11/1778 (Item 17)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Rains Cook for Six Men, 09/14/1778 (Item 18)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Rains Cook for Six Men, 09/16/1778 (Item 19)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Rains Cook for Seven Men, 09/18/1778 (Item 20)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers and Privates of the 3rd Regiment Signed by Rains Cook for Seven Artificers and Three Privates, [09/21/1778] (Item 21)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Regiment Signed by John Manly for Eight Articers and One Man on Furlough, 09/30/1778 (Item 22)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by John Manly for Seven Men, 10/01/1778 (Item 23)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Regiment Signed by Isaac Hicks for Nine Men, 10/[18]/1778 (Item 24)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Thomas Threadgill for Six Men, 10/30/1778 (Item 25)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by Isaac Hicks for Seven Men of the [Illegible] Regiment, 11/08/1778 (Item 26)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by John Wandin for One Woman and One Child, 11/10/1778-11/14/1778 (Item 27)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by William Scott, 11/10/1778 (Item 28)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Gideon Booker for Five Men, 11/13/1778 (Item 29)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Regiment Signed by Isaac Hicks Belonging to the 3rd Regiment and Some Discharged, 11/14?/1778 (Item 30)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by John Wandin for Three Artificers, [One Woman and One Child], 11/[14]/1778 (Item 31)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers of the 3rd Battalion Signed by Illegible for Five Men, 11/20/1778 (Item 32)
        - Provision Return for the Artificers Signed by Robert Howe [Fragment], 11/20/1778 (Item 33)
    - Subseries IX: Provision Returns for the Artillery, undated, 1778
      This subseries contains 212 Provision Returns for the Artillery Unit of the Continental Army of Georgia, primarily signed by Charles Noel Romand de Lisle. De Lisle was a French Captain who came to America with the Lafayette Expedition. He was made Major of the Artillery by George Washington and served from 1776 to 1778. Names appearing among these Provision Returns are: Thomas Sutton, George Young, Will Johnston, James Alexander, Shadrack Wright, Francis Huger, Saban Johnston, Andrew McFarland, John Francis Detrevillie, Thomas Wright, John Tweedel, Elijah Wilson, Andrew McFarland, Richard [Rick] Watkins, Charles Murrino, James Cherry, Chris Hillary, Andrew Templeton, John Mason, George St. George, John Wandin, and "Capt. Defau." Companies specifically mentioned are the First Continental Artillery Company, the "Late Capt. Lee's First Company of Artillery," the Third Artillery, the 1stBattalion, the 5thSouth Carolina, and the Artillery Fatigue Company. Savannah, Tybee Island, Fort Howe, and Read's Bluff are places mentioned in the returns. One Provision Return provides for the Artillery and Wagoners (#74) and several returns contain lists of those provided for.
      - (Binder 9)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Thomas Sutton [Fragment], undated (Item 1)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Unknown, undated (Item 2)
        - Provision Return [for the Artillery] Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for Back Rations Due to De Lisle, 12/05/1777-04/15/1778 (Item 3)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by George Young Who Complains that His Company has Received No Small Beer Since 12/15/1777, WPA_B-0289; Indexed #117 (Item 4)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for Back Rations Due Thomas Sutton, 12/15/1777-01/15/1778 (Item 5)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Will Johnston for William Johnston, 12/15/1777-03/28/1778 (Item 6)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle, 1778 (Item 7)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for Lt. [Thomas] Sutton Belonging to His Grade, 02/1778; WPA_C-0180; Indexed #123 (Item 8)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by George young for Forty Men of the First Continental Artillery Company, 02/2?/1778 (Item 9)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery By Capt. Young for the First Company [Fragment], 02/14/1778 (Item 10)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by William Johnson for Twenty People of the First Company, 02/14/1778 (Item 11)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by James Alexander for the First Company at Tybee Island, 02/17/1778 (Item 12)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by George [Young] for Capt [Liew] Company, 02/21/1778 (Item 13)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Thomas Sutton for Lt. Sutton and One Man Under the Command of Major Romand, 02/24/1778 (Item 14)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by George Young, 02/25/1778 (Item 15)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for Back Rations for Saban Johnston, 02/28/1778-04/15/1778; WPA_C-0172; Indexed #122 (Item 16)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed By Charles Noel Romand De Lisle Delivered to Lt. Sutton, 03/1778 (Item 17)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by George Young for the First Artillery Company, 03/04/1778 (Item 18)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for His [Weater] and His Boy, 03/07/1778 (Item 19)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Thomas [Illegible] Received Rations from James Farquharson, 03/09/1778 (Item 20)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for His [Weater], His Boy, and Three Men Belonging to the Artillery, 03/10/1778 (Item 21)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Sheftall Sheftall for the Late Capt. Lee's First Company of Artillery, 03/11/1778 (Item 22)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles By Noel Romand De Lisle Delivered to Lt. [Sutton?], Slightly Illegible, 03/14/1778 (Item 23)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Charles By Noel Romand De Lisle, 03/17/1778 (Item 24)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed By Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for the Third Company, 03/17/1778 (Item 25)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed By Charles Noel Romand De Lisle, 03/18/1778 (Item 26)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed By George Young for Twenty men of His Company in Savannah, 03/19/1778 (Item 27)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed By Charles Noel Romand De Lisle, 03/21/1778 (Item 28)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed By Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for the Twelve Men of the [Illegible] Company, 03/21/1778 (Item 29)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle, 03/23/1778 (Item 30)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle, 03/24/1778 (Item 31)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for Lt. Fuller, 03/24/1778 (Item 32)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by George Young for Forty-two men in the First Artillery Company, 03/24/1778 (Item 33)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by George Young for the First Artillery Company, 03/24/1778 (Item 34)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle with List of Soldiers, 03/25?/1778 (Item 35)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for the Third Artillery Company, 03/27/1778 (Item 36)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for Him and His [Weater], 03/27/1778 (Item 37)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle, 03/28/1778 (Item 38)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for the Third Artillery Company, 03/28/1778 (Item 39)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Artificers Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for Twenty-Four Artificers, 03/29/1778-04/01/1778 (Item 40)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle, 03/30/1778 (Item 41)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by George Young for the First Artillery Company, 03/31/1778 (Item 42)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for George Young's Artillery Company, 04/[?]/1778 (Item 43)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Artificers Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for Twenty-four Men, 04/02/1778 (Item 44)
        - Provision Return for the Artillery Signed by Charles Noel Romand De Lisle for Back Rations Due to March for the Last Expedition, 04/06/1778 (Item 45)